Guide to the Rebecca Spring Papers, ca. 1830-1900
Department of Special Collections
Rebecca Spring Papers,
ca. 1830-1900
Special Collections M0541
Spring, Rebecca.
1 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Rebecca's grandson, Herbert Peet Heron, inherited the papers which remained in storage until March, 1990. Purchased, June, 1990.
Biographical Note
Daughter of Arnold Buffum, Rebecca (1811-1911) married Marcus Spring (1810-1874) in approximately 1840. She a Quaker, he a philanthropic New York businessman, both became intensely involved in liberal political and social affairs and were part of the abolitionist, feminist, and transcendentalist movements. They were long-time friends of Fredrika Bremer, Lydia Maria Child, Margaret Fuller, and Elizabeth Palmer Peabody. Rebecca worked hard but unsuccessfully for abolitionist John Brown's acquittal, then later for the commuting of his sentence. Marcus Spring was active in cooperative societies and instrumental in the founding of two communities based on the teachings of Charles Fourier - The North American Phalanx and The Raritan Bay Union - the latter which was located on his estate in Eagleswood, New Jersey. In the late 1850s Spring founded the Eagleswood Military Academy. After Marcus' death, Rebecca continued their work in liberal political and social causes for another 25 years. In the late 1890s, she moved to southern California to live with her daughter, Jeanie Peet, where she became involved with many of the local artists and writers.
Scope and Content
Incoming correspondence (ca. 200 letters) from American and European political, religious, and literary figures. Manuscript of Rebecca Spring's memoirs (191 p.), ca. 1900.
Container List
- Incoming correspondence (including selected names mentioned in letters).
  - [Anonymous]. 1 AL, 3 pp. [n.d.]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alcott, Amos Bronson. See Bremer, Fredrika.
  - Alden, Henry M. 1 ALS, 2 pp., March 21, 1898.Editor of Harper's Magazine. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anderson, Hans Christian. See Bremer, Fredrika; Scudder, Horace E.; Wulff, Henriette; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 99, 100, 104, 105.
  - Anderson, Robert. 1 sentiment, 1 p., May 17, 1867.Major General U.S.A., Commander of Fort Sumter when first shot fired. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arms, [?] P. 1 ALS, 2 pp., Sept. 21, 1860. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arnold, George B. 2 ALS, 7 pp., June 16, 1856; June 18 [?], 1856.Poet and artist, associated with the New York Bohemian group. See also R. Spring's typescript, p. 85. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arnold, Matthew. 1 ANS, 1 p., Feb. 4, 1884.See also R. Spring's typescript, pp. 31, 32. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Austen, Jane. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 57.
  - Avis, John. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 164, for the copy of a letter from Avis to her, dated Dec. 9, 1859. Jailor.
  - Baillie, Joanna. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 29, 56-58.
  - Bancroft, Elizabeth. 1 ALS, 2 pp., [n.d.]. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bancroft, George and Charlotte. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 6, 55.
  - Barrett-Browning, Elizabeth. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 50-52, 90.
  - Burton, Warren. 1 ALS, 2 pp., Dec. 31, 1840/Jan. 1, 1841[postscript]. Mentions [George?] Ripley; the Antislavery League. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Beecher, Catherine. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 85.
  - Beecher, Henry Ward. See Bremer, Fredrika; and R. Spring's typescript, p. 85.
  - Bellows, Henry Whitney. 9 ALS, 21 pp., March 29, 1852; [?], 1858; [1859]; Oct. 5, 1860; April 6, 1861; Feb. 23, 1871; March 13, 1871; June 17, 1874; Aug. 24, 1874;2 incomplete letters, 1 dated April 4, 1857.Unitarian clergyman, Founder and President of the U.S. Sanitary Commission during the Civil War. See also Bremer, Fredrika; Child, Lydia Maria. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bernhard, Sarah. See E. Photographs.
  - Birney, W.B. 2 ALS, 2 pp., July 15, 1860; Dec. 31, 1864.Lawyer, General. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Blackwell, Elizabeth. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 35, 36.
  - Bodichon, Barbara Lee Smith. 3 ALS, 3 pp., Aug. 17, 1950; April 7, [n.y.]; [n.d.].English artist and reformer. See also Griffith, Mattie. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bremer, Fredrika. 28 ALS, 127 pp., 1 p. of proverbs, and 1 sketch, 8 pp. (dated April 1850,about Jenny Lind). Letters: Oct. 20, 1849; Dec. 9, 1849; Jan. 3, 1850; March [1], [1850]; July 26, 1850; Sept. 11, 1850; July 13, 1851; May 13, 1853; June 10, 1853; Dec. 12, 1853; Sept. 21, 1854; April 26, 1855; [Sept.] 1855; May 14, 1856; Nov. 7, 1856; Sept. 24, 1857; Nov. 24, 1857; Jan. 25, 1858; Feb. 20, 1861; Aug. 19, 1861; Nov. 10, 1861; March 10, 1862; March 26, 1862; Sept. 1, 1863[incomplete]; Feb. 17, 1864; April 1, 1864; April 27, 1865; June 19, 1865. 1 a.l., [n.d.].Present are also later typed transcripts of several of the letters [Jan. 3, 1850; Feb. 20, 1850; July 3, 1851; June 10, 1853; Aug. 10, 1861; March 26, 1862; April 10, 1862; Sept. 1, 1863; Feb. 17, 1864; April 1, 1864,3 incomplete letters]. Bremer, a Swedish writer (1801-1865),was close to the American transcendentalists. This is an interesting and extensive correspondence reflecting Bremer's impressions of political and literary events in Europe and America. See also Child, Lydia Maria; Griffith, Mattie; Howitt, Mary; Lowell, James Russell; Sedgwick, Catharine Maria; Whittier, John Greenleaf; Wulff, Henriette; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 82-84, 95, 102-105. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Brown, Henry Kirke. 2 ALS, 6 pp., Sept. 15, 1857; June 24, 1861.Sculptor. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brown, John. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 129-133, for her copy of a letter from John Brown to her, dated Nov. 24, 1859;p. 138 for part of a letter from John Brown to Aaron D. Stevens, dated Dec. 2, 1859;and pp. 133-135 for her typescript copy of a letter from John Brown's widow to her, dated April 6, 1862.Related material: 1 AL, 8 pp., Feb. 13. 1860;1 ALS, 4 pp., June 3, [n.y.],signed [Mrs. Bill Mulaby (?)]; 1 list of various items. See also Birney, W.B.; Child, Lydia Maria; Clarke, James Freeman; Hunter, Andrew; Redpath, James; Sennott, George; Thompson, Ruth Brown; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 14, 113, 117, 118, 120-127, 129-138, 151, 152, 160-162, 167, 170, 172-174. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Browne, Albert. See Griffith, Mattie.
  - Browning, Robert. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 51.
  - Bryant, William Cullen. 5 ALS, 6 pp., Sept. 4, 1855; Nov. 4, 1859; Oct. 15, 1861; Nov. 20, 1861; Nov. 27, 1867.Including a gift of pressed flowers, [G]iven in their garden at Boston the Sunday [?] of our pleasant visit by Mr & Mrs Bryant. Sept. 17, 1865.See also R. Spring's typescript, pp. 7, 8, 20. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Buffum, Arnold. Rebecca Spring's father. See Birney, W.B.; Bryant, William Cullen; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 61, 85, 87.
  - Burkhart, Lillian. 1 TNS, 1 p., [n.d.].Best-known actress on the American vaudeville stage. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Burney, Fanny. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 56, 57.
  - Burns, Robert. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 46, 49, 51, 88.
  - Burton - see `Barton'
  - Byron, George Lord Gordon. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 29, 36, 56, 88.
  - [Calve], Emma. 1 ALS, 2 pp., [n.d.], [1902].In French. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carlyle, Jane. 1 ALS, 3 pp., Aug. [185-].See also R. Spring's typescript, pp. 48, 49, 52-54, 91. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carlyle, Thomas. See Channing, William Ellery; Newberg, Thomas; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 48-54, 91.
  - Chadwick, John White. 1 ALS, 4 pp., July 13, 1871. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Channing, William Ellery. d. 1842 2 ALS, 13 pp., [Jan. 31, 1837]; Jan. 5, 1838;Channing goes into detail about his current activities, whether or not to give up the pulpit, his thoughts about socialism as a religion, etc. See also Bremer, Fredrika; Emerson, Ralph Waldo; Frothingham, Octavius Brooks; Fuller, Margaret; Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Channing, William Henry. d. 1902, 2 ALS, 3 pp Apr 21 1851, [UNK] 8 pp Sept 21 1874. See Fuller, Margaret; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 3, 4, 44, 82, 85, 176 [typed copy of a letter by Channing, dated Sept. 4, 1874], 180.
  - Chase, Salmon P. 3 ALS, 3 pp., Dec. 7, 1870; Feb. 23, 1871; Aug. 10, 1874.Chief Justice during Reconstruction. See also Bodichon, Barbara; and D. Invitations. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cheney, Seth. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 80.
  - Child, Lydia Maria. 14 ALS, 43 pp., Jan 17, 1848; Sept. 21, 1851; Jan. 18, 1852; Jan. 8, 1857; Nov. 18, 1859; Feb. 5, 1860; March 19, 1860; Feb. 6, 1862; March 25, 1862; Feb. 26, 1875;4 letters undated; 1 incomplete letter, dated Dec. 18, 1864.An interesting series of letters. Child and the Springs were close friends, and Child goes into great detail about current events, the anti-slavery movement (of which she says the demon of theology introduced division into its ranks), her financial situation with her husband on their Northhampton farm, the Civil War, the North American Phalanx society, the events surrounding John Brown's trial and execution, Margaret Fuller and Fredrika Bremer. See Bremer, Fredrika; Child, Lydia Maria; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 82, 110, 111, 113, 114, 116, 121, 168-170 [typed copy of part of a letter by L.M. Child, dated March 19, 1860]. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clarke, James Freeman. 3 ALS, 6 pp. & 1 photographic portrait of Clarke. June 21, 1861; Nov. 20, 1879; Jan. 28, 1885.See E. Photographs for the portrait. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clay, Cassius Marcellus. 3 ALS, 6 pp., April 8, 1895; May 21, 1895; Dec. 30, 1897.1 incomplete letter by Rebecca Spring; 1 newspaper clipping about Cassius M. Clay's Child Wife returning home. See also Washington, Brooker T.; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 12, 17. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne. 1 photographic ALS, 2 pp., second page double, Nov. 6, 1898. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Colerigde, Samuel Taylor. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 29.
  - Collyer, Robert. 1 ALS, 2 pp., Dec. 10, 1899.Rev. Robert Collyer. Famous Congregationalist Clergyman of Chicago, very popular, immense following. English blacksmith, graduated into the clergy. See also R. Spring's typescript, p. 85. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Coppoc, Edwin and Barklay. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 163-165. Includes acknowledgment of money sent to the Coppocs by R. Spring.
  - Crowe, Catherine. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 33.
  - Curtis, George William. 3 ALS and 1 TLS, 9 pp., Sept. 12, 1863; Oct. 26, 1864; June 18, 1872; Sept. 16, 1887.See also Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer; and R. Spring's typescript, p. 85. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - De Quincey, Thomas. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 33.
  - Dewey, Orville. 4 ALS, 11 pp., Jan. 27, 1849; Jan. 17, 1851, [n.d.]; Aug. 26, 1874. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Douglass, Frederick. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 2, 34.
  - Dowding, W.C. 1 ALS, 8 pp., May 2, 1848.See also Bremer, Fredrika. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Ehrenheim, Peha von. 3 ALS, 9 pp., April 19, 1888; [March] 15, 1891; June 8, 1894.Count Peha von Ehrenheim. Swedish Count. Statesman. High in political life of Sweden. Next in importance to the King. Ehrenheim traveling [...?] met Rebecca Spring, and they became close friends. Later, Marcus and Rebecca Spring dining with Queen of Sweden, met Ehrenheim in his right [?] position. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Eltz, Louis von. 1 ALS, 2 pp., Aug. 5, 1885.Baron Louis von Eltz. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo. 1 ALS, 3 pp. Dated Concord, July 23, 1850.See R. Spring's typescript, p. 80 1/2, for a copy of this letter (in R. Spring's handwriting). To Marcus Spring, concerning the sudden death of Margaret Fuller - who has just died at sea a few days before. Emerson tells Spring that he is sending his good friend, Henry D. Thoreau, to represent him and Fuller's other friends at the sight of the accident and that Thoreau has been instructed to recover as much of Fuller's manuscripts, etc., that can be found. See also Fuller, Margaret; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 43, 48, 50, 81-84. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Everett, Edward. 1 ALS, 2 pp., June 14, 1863.See also R. Spring's typescript, pp. 55, 56. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Fields, James Thomas. See Higginson, Thomas Wentworth.
  - Follen, Charles. 6 ALS, 17 pp., Feb. 23, 1839; April 1, 1839; Jan. 3, 1841; Aug. 18, [n.y.]; Nov. 13, [n.y.]; [n.d.].A couple of these letters are from Follen's wife. First professor of German Literature at Harvard, abolitionist and Unitarian clergyman. See also Channing, William Ellery; Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Fremont, Jessie Benton. 1 ALS, 4 pp., Sept. 30, 1890. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Fremont, John Charles. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 86.
  - Frothingham, Octavius Brooks. 3 ALS, 5 pp., April 11, 1885; Oct. 23, 1885; May 25, 1886.Radical religious and literary figure. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Fuller, Sarah Margaret. 5 ALS, 17 pp., April 17, 1844; June 12, [1845]; June 7, 1846; Feb. 1, 1848; March 9, 1849;1 incomplete letter. 1 copy of an incomplete letter, in R. Spring's handwriting (see pp. 78 and 79 of her typescript), [n.d.].Written from Cambridge, Brooklyn, and Rome. The letters from Rome discuss Fuller's friendship with Guiseppe Mazzini, the exiled leader of the Italian republican movement, and at one point she says that she wishes her two brothers, Emerson and Channing could see him. In another letter from Rome, Fuller discusses her poor health and depression, Harriet Martineau and Mrs. Trollope. See also Arnold, Matthew; Bremer, Fredrika; Child, Lydia Maria; Emerson, Ralph Waldo; Julian, George W.; Thom, William; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 1-6, 24, 25, 27, 28, 32-34, 37-48, 50-53, 55, 58, 60-62, 64-69, 78-82. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Garrison, William Lloyd. 1 ALS, 1 p., March 14, 1860.Margins trimmed, with some loss of text. Declines an invitations, comments on the bloody vindictiveness of the Virginians, and sends his regards to Sarah Grimke, the Welds, etc. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 34, 171 [typed copy of that identical letter from Garrison, complete], 178. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Gillies, Margaret. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 59.
  - Gillies, Mary. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 59.
  - Gilman, Charlotte Perkins. 1 ALS, 3 pp., July 7, 1904. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Godwin, Fanny Bryant. 3 ALS, 7 pp., not dated but probably late 1860s (1) & 1870s.Daughter of William Cullen Bryant; wife of Parke Godwin. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 44.
  - Goldman, Emma. 1 ALS, 1 p., dated April 29, [n.y.]. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Greeley, Horace. 4 ALS, 7 pp., Dec. [?]. 1853, Nov. 4, 1855; Dec. 5, 1855; Jan. 14, 1872.See also MacKaye, James Morrison Steele; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 1, 3, 5. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Griffith, Mattie. 4 ALS, 20 pp., Sept. 23, [n.y.]; July 7, [n.y.]; July 8, 1857; Dec. 19, [n.y.].Kentucky poet and abolitionist, who freed her slaves and moved to New York in the 1850s where she later married Albert Browne, an editor of the N.Y. Tribune. On the well-known voyage of the Great Eastern, when that ship became disabled in the Channel, 30 silk dresses and much of Mrs. Browne's jewelry were ground to pulp by the lurching sides of the vessel. The first three letters are from Griffith's early period in the North, and she goes into detail about her living situation, the help she has received from Mrs. Charlotte Follen, Miss Peabody, Miss Child, etc. The last is a letter of condolence to Mrs. Spring about the death of her husband, Marcus. See also Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer; and R. Spring's typescript, p. 86. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Grimke, Sarah Moore. See Bodichon, Barbara; Garrison, William Lloyd; Peabody, Elizabeth; and R. Spring's typescript, p. 171.
  - Harte, Bret. 1 photographic ALS, 3 pp., June 21, [n.y.]. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Haslett, Absalom. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 160, 168, 171.
  - Hicks, Thomas. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 64.
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth. 5 ALS, 7 pp., Jan 25. 1860; Jan. 22, 1884; Jan. 30, 1884; Feb. [?] 25, 1897; Sept. 14, 1907.Brief notes, but the last, written to Mrs. Spring when both Higginson and Spring were advanced in age, notes You and I are among the few oldest among the survivors of the transcendental & anti-slavery period. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell. 1 LS, 1 p., Feb. 8, 1889. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Howitt, Mary. 7 ALS, 25 pp., Aug. 19, 1848; March 12, 1864; Dec. 14, 1874; Jan. 14, [n.y.]; March 12, [n.y.];2 undated letters. English author. See also Bremer, Fredrika; Greeley, Horace; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 55, 59, 90-94. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Howitt, William. 4 ALS, 10 pp., not dated, but ca. 1850s.One letter is burned around the edges, with some loss of text. English author, husband of Mary Howitt. See also R. Spring's typescript, pp. 55, 59, 90, 92-94. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Hugo, Victor. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 172-174 [typed copy of An appeal from Victor Hugo to the American Nation, dated Dec. 2, 1859].
  - Hunt, Leigh. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 59.
  - Hunter, Andrew. 2 ALS, 3 pp., Dec. 24, 1859; Feb. 22, 1860.Hunter was the prosecuting attorney in the John Brown trial and writes to Mrs. Spring about his opinions on the trial, Brown's character and the treatment of him in prison. See also Sennott, George; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 136-137 [part of a typed letter from R. Spring to A. Hunter, dated Jan. 2, 1860],165. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Inness, George. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 85.
  - Irlman, Mary C. 1 ALS, 4 pp., June 8, 1910.Niece to Rebecca Spring. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - James, Henry. 1 ALS, 2 pp., first part missing, [n.d.].Writes about anti-slavary; arctic calamity (Captain Luca). (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Johnson, Samuel. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 30, 31, 56, 57.
  - Julian, George W. 1 ALS, 4 pp., Sept. 16, 1885.U.S. Senator, U.S. Surveyor-General for New Mexico. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Kingsley, Charles. 1 ALS, 3 pp., Jan. 26, 1853. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Kirkland, Mrs. [Caroline Matilda Stansbury?]. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 82, 84.
  - Koch, Ida. 1 ALS, 4 pp., [Oct.] 20, [18--].Born Wulff. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Lamb, Charles. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 55.
  - Letcher, John. 1 ALS, 1 p., March 14, 1860.Governor. Permission in the letter given to Marcus Spring to remove the bodies of Stevens and Harrison. See also R. Spring's typescript, p. 155. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Lewes, George. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 50, 51.
  - Lincoln, Abraham. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 61.
  - Lind, Jenny. See Bremer, Fredrika; Child, Lydia Maria; and R. Spring's typescript, p. 82.
  - Lindley, Charles [?]. 1 ALS, 4 pp., April 20, 1867. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Longfellow, Samuel. 1 ALS, 2 pp., Sept. 30, [n.y.].Brother of Henry Wadsworth Longfellow. Poet himself; minister (Unitarian). See also R. Spring's typescript, pp. 82, 85. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Lowell, Josephine Shaw. 1 ALS, 4 pp., Dec. 16, 1900. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Lowell, James Russell. 2 ANS, 2 pp., July 1, 1850; Jan. 7, 1884.See also Bremer, Fredrika; and R. Spring's typescript, p. 172 [poem by Lowell, untitled]. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - MacKaye, James Morrison Steele. 5 ALS, 21 pp., July 7, 1862; Nov. 4, 1862; Dec. 7, 1869; July 14, 1871; Sept. 12, 1872.1 incomplete letter. MacKaye, playwright, actor, author and inventor, was married to Spring's daughter, Jeanie Spring. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Martineau, Harriet. See Fuller, Margaret; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 24, 31, 48, 61, 175 [typed copy of part of a letter from H. Martineau, dated Jan. 24, 1868].
  - Mazzini, Guiseppe. See Fuller, Margaret; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 52, 57, 59, 68, 91.
  - Mickiewicz, Adam. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 64.
  - Mill, John Stuart. 1 ALS, 3 pp., June 21, 1870. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Moore, Tom. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 29, 56, 88.
  - Newberg, Thomas. 4 ALS, 18 pp., Feb. 22, 1862; Sept. 6, 1862; June 2, 1862; June 2, 1863.Carlyle's secretary. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Odenheimer, W.A. 2 ALS, 2 pp., July 10, 1863; March 5 [?], 1872.Bishop of New Jersey. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Ossoli, Angelo. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 64, 80.
  - Owen, Robert Dale. 1 ALS, 4 pp., Sept. 10, 1865.A letter concerning Spring's donation or loan towards furnishing a place for Mattie Griffith in New York. See Griffith, Mattie; Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Page, William. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 85.
  - Parker, Wayne. 1 ALS, 1 p., Feb. 13, 1880.U.S. Senator from New Jersey. (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Parkman, [Francis?]. See Howitt, Mary.
  - Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer. 17 ALS, 75 pp., 1 damaged letter. The letters, which are not all dated by year, appear to be written between about 1840 and 1865; they cover a wide variety of subjects, including education, Mattie Griffith's difficult life in Boston, Sarah Grimke and Peabody's financial arrangements with the Springs. See Griffith, Mattie; and R. Spring's typescript, p. 85. (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Phillips, Wendell. See Child, Lydia Maria; Garrison, William Lloyd; Griffith, Mattie; and R. Spring's typescript, p. 171.
  - Plympton, Eben. See E. Photographs.
  - Poe, Edgar Allan. See R. Spring's typecript, p. 6.
  - Quincey, Edmund. 1 ALS, 4 pp., July 5, 1840 [?].Rebecca Spring knew him well. Distinguished man of a distinguished family [note on an envelope attached to the letter]. (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Raymond, J.H.[?]. 1 ALS, 4 pp., July 21, 1860 [?]. (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Realf, Richard. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 161, 162 [poem by Realf, entitled Unseen].
  - [Rearny], J.L. 1 ALS, 6 pp., June 15, 1903.With an amateur snapshot, 1902.See E. Photographs. (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Redpath, James. 1 ALS, 4 pp., Feb. 4, 1860.N.Y. editor and author. Concerning John Brown and the publication of a book about him. See also Child, Lydia Maria. (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Reynolds, Joshua. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 56, 57.
  - Ripley, [George?]. See Barton, Warren; Follen, Charles.
  - Scott, Walter. See R. Spring's typescript, pp. 29, 37, 38, 56, 88.
  - Scudder, Horace E. 1 ALS, 1 p., Oct. 26, 1869. (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Sedgwick, Catharine Maria. 1 ALS, 3 pp. [incomplete], Aug. 185[?].See also Dewey, Orville. (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Sennott, George. 3 ALS, 7 pp., Nov. 15, 1859; Dec. 30, 1859; Jan. 6, 1860.Concerning the events surrounding the defense of John Brown and associates. Sennott, a Boston attorney, was a counsel for Brown. See also Brown, John; Child, Lydia Maria; Higginson, Thomas Wentworth; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 118, 124, 141, 165-167 [typed copies of 2 letters from Sennott to R. Spring, dated Dec. 14, 1859; and Jan. 6, 1860;the latter one includes a letter by Aaron Stevens, Aaron Dwight Stevens' father, to Sennott, dated Jan. 4, 1860],169. (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Shaw, Francis George. 1 ALS, 4 pp., Jan. 9, 1853.Father of Josephine Shaw Lowell & Col. Robert Shaw, killed at Fort Donaldson. (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Shelley, Percy Bysshe. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 57.
  - Sigourney, Mrs. [Lydia Howard Huntley?]. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 7.
  - Southey, Robert. See R. Spring's typescript, p. 29.
  - Spring, Marcus. 1 ALS, 1 p., July 29, 1836.To Rebecca Buffum, later Rebecca Spring. 1 cabinet photograph, ca. 1873. See E. Photographs; and R. Spring's typescript, pp. 1, 6, 7, 14, 16, 20, 38-42, 44-48, 51, 59-63, 80, 83, 84, 90, 95, 109, 110, 127, 149, 158, 161, 171, 175-177. (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Spring, Rebecca. See B. Manuscripts, C. Newspaper clippings about Rebecca Spring, and E. Photographs.
  - Spring, William. 4 ALS, 18 pp., Dec. 3, 1987; Sept. 5, 1898; June 14, 1898; July 6, 1900. (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - [Spring, William]. 1 ALS, 2 pp., [n.d.].Rebecca and Marcus Spring's son. (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - [Spring, (?)]. 1 ALS, 4 pp., April 26, 1861/April 28, 1861. (Box 2, Folder 78)